

## **Yanick Senn**

**E-Mail** info@yanicksenn.com

Website yanicksenn.com
GitHub qithub.com/yanicksenn

Highlights Java, Kotlin, C#, SQL, Maven, Docker, Spring,

Typescript, Angular, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

## **Summary**

Skilled software engineer with 6+ years of working experience and a BSc in Computer Science. A quick learner who can absorb and contribute new ideas and concepts. Always pushing to reduce technical debt and optimizing processes in software development. Reliable team player with strong oral and written communication skills. Staying in the loop through contributions to open-source and personal projects.

### **Education**

**ZHAW School of Engineering**BSc in Computer Science

Zürich
2018 – 2022

BBB Berufsbildung BadenBadenFederal VET Diploma (Application developer EFZ)2012 – 2016Vocational baccalaureate (BMS)2012 – 2016

## **Experience**

### **Worldline Schweiz AG**

# Software-Engineer

• Developed and maintained software to handle the processing of card payments.

- Held technical interviews with potential new employees.
- Took ownership in various projects regarding PCI DSS.
- Presented newly developed components and tools in department wide trainings.

PL/SQL Spring Eclipse-RCP Docker Maven Java Kotlin Shell

# aXenta AG 2016 – Jan. 2021

#### Software-Engineer (Full Stack)

- Developed and maintained a web-interface called PKCockpit for second-pillar pension funds.
- Developed specific web services for clients based on JAX-RS.
- Held company internal trainings for unit, integration, and property-based testing.
- Organized a company internal hackathon to evaluate a suitable web-framework for PKCockpit.

Angular PL/SQL EJB2 / EJB3 AWT/Swing Gradle Java TypeScript HTML/CSS

# aXenta AG 2012 – 2016

#### Software-Engineer Apprentice

- Resolved software bugs and participated in company internal projects.
- Implemented an iOS application that allows full-text search for Swiss laws.
- Developed a tool to unify and automate screenshots for release manuals of new features. (IPA)

Java PL/SQL EJB2 / EJB3 AWT/Swing Objective-C Batch

1

Zürich

Feb. 2021 - Now

# Languages

## **Frameworks & Tools**

Java	6 y.	Maven	6 y.
Kotlin	3 y.	Spring / Spring-Boot	4 y.
C#	2 y.	Angular	2 y.
SQL / PL/SQL	6 y.	Unity3d	3 y.
TypeScript	2 y.	Docker	4 y.
JavaScript / HTML / CSS	3 y.	Jenkins	4 y.
Shell / Bash / Batch / PowerShell	3 y.	Node.js	2 y.

# **Additional information**

### Non programming languages

- German (Mother tongue)
- English

### **Interests**

- Motorsports (Go-Kart in Swiss National Championship)
- Game-Development
- Gaming
- Drums